Finding Aid for the Alfred Leonard and Joseph Leonard Collection PASC-M.0180
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Correspondence, Series III.
  - P. Alfred Leonard and Others, Subseries 6.
    - [Letters to Alfred Leonard]. 16 leaves; 2 cards; 2 postcards; 3 envelopes. (Box 6, Folder 8)
      Letters dating from December 26, 1942 - April 15, 1974 in English. 2 letters undated; remainder in chronological order.
    - Davison, Stephen; Rubin, Eleanor. [Email correspondence regarding Leonard collection]. printout; 57 pp. (Box 6, Folder 9)
      Email correspondence dating from January 20, 1997 - May 10, 2001 between Eleanor Rubin, daughter of Alfred Leonard, and Stephen Davison, Director of UCLA Performing Arts Special Collections Archives regarding items in collection to be donated and information about Alfred and Joseph Leonard.
    - Rubin, Eleanor. [Postcard to Stephen Davison]. postcard. (Box 6, Folder 16)
      Postcard from Eleanor Rubin's gallery (Alfred Leonard's daughter) re: 2nd volume of Leonard CD transfer from older recordings.
    - [Leonard, Alfred]. [Letter to Herr Einstein]. mimeograph; 1 leaf. (Box 17, Folder 10)
      Original location in folder "Alfred Leonard: writings". Letter in German dated November 3, 1934.
    - [Leonard, Alfred]. [Letter to Herr Ueberle]. typewritten ms; 2 leaves. (Box 17, Folder 11)
      Original location in folder "Alfred Leonard: writings". Letter in German dated July 12, 1932.
    - [Letter to Selective Service Board]. 1 leaf. (Box 21, Folder 32)
      Letter dated December 14, 1940 regarding questionaire.
    - [Letter from Alfred Leonard to Jerome Lachenbruch]. carbon copy; 1 leaf. (Box 21, Folder 37)
      Letter dated August 9, 1934 from Jake Zeitlin Books.
    - [Letters from Senator Abe Ribicoff regarding IRS query]. 5 leaves. (Box 21, Folder 39)
      5 items: letter dated July 13, 1971 from Senator Abe Ribicoff; letter dated July 16, 1971 from Senator Abe Ribicoff; letter dated July 15, 1971 from Sol Mosher, US Department of Commerce to Ribicoff; cover letter from Abe Ribicoff with IRS letter; letter from IRS to Senator Abe Ribicoff dated July 20, 1971.
    - [Letter to Gateway to Music Bulletin subscribers]. 4 p. (Box 24, Folder 3)
      Open letter dated January 8, 1943.
  - Joseph Leonard, Subseries 7.
    - [Members of Los Angeles Jewish Community organizations]. [Letters from Jewish organizations and Joseph Leonard 1960-1973]. 6 leaves; 1 envelope. (Box 6, Folder 10)
      6 items: letter dated January 16, 1960 from Dr. Anneliese Landau, Music Director of the Westside Jewish Community Center thanking Joseph for his performance and enclosing check for musical services; letter dated October 1, 1963 from Joseph Harris, President of Temple Beth Am thanking Joseph for performance and directing of choir; letter dated December 27, 1963 from Joseph to Temple Beth Am choir; letter dated October 20, 1965 from Nathan Shapell, President of Temple Beth Am thanking Joseph for music during High Holy Days; letter dated October 21, 1965 from Chairman, Cantor and Rabbi of Temple Beth Am thanking Joseph for musical services; letter dated May 8, 1973 from Alfred Leonard to Mr. Louis Wolfe, Chairman of Personnel Committee of Olympic Jewish Temple and Center regarding Joseph's payment and benefits.
    - Alfred Leonard; Jacob Pressman. [Letters regarding celebration of Joseph Leonard's 70th birthday]. 7 leaves. (Box 6, Folder 11)
      6 items, all letters regarding arrangements for celebration: letter dated June 18, 1973 from Alfred Leonard to Rabbi Jacob Pressman of Temple Beth Am; letter dated July 5, 1973 from Rabbi Jacob Pressman responding to Alfred Leonard's letter; letter dated July 30, 1973 from Alfred Leonard to Louis Kotzen, Executive Director of Temple Beth Am; letter dated July 30, 1973 from Alfred Leonard to Rabbi Pressman; letter dated July 30, 1973 from Alfred Leonard to Mrs. Arbit; letter dated August 14, 1973 from Alfred Leonard to Mrs. Arbit enclosing check.
    - Martinson, Marjorie; [Castelnuovo-Tedesco?], Mario; Leonard, Joseph; Pera, Ama. [Personal letters to Joseph Leonard]. 6 leaves; 1 envelope. (Box 6, Folder 12)
      5 items: letter dated February 24, 1943 from Marjorie Martinson regarding lessons; letter dated May 31, 1961 from Mario [Castelnuovo-Tedesco?] relating European concerts and reviews; cover letter dated July 12, 1961 from Joseph Leonard to Heinz Zacharais regarding enclosed reviews from Europe [not enclosed here] with pencilled in clarifications by Eleanor Rubin; letter dated August 7, 1963 from "Joey" Leonard, nephew of Joseph Leonard concerning personal and family news; undated letter from Ama Pera regarding personal news and report on Isaac Stern's concert in Israel.
    - Compinsky, Alec; Leonard, Joseph. [Cover letter, contract, program from Pacific Institute of Music and Fine Art]. 5 leaves, 1 envelope. (Box 6, Folder 13)
      5 items: cover letter, contract and notary seal dated January 22, 1936 inviting Joseph to teach at Pacific Institute; response dated March 3, 1936 accepting offer; program for Pacific Institute of Music and Fine Art.
    - Pera, Al; Leonard, Joseph. [Letters between Al Pera and Joseph Leonard with clippings]. 5 leaves; 2 newspaper clippings; 1 envelope. (Box 6, Folder 14)
      5 items: 1 leaf letter dated June 23, 1964 in Italian from Al Pera to Guiseppe [Joseph] Leonard, with questions on back from Joseph about Italian-German translations; 4 leaves typed sentences with responses from Al Pera in pen; clipping from Italian newspaper announcing concert of Mario Castelnuovo Tedesco; Italian newspaper clipping "Per la serie 'Vivere insieme'; envelope dated June 25, 1964 from Italy.
    - [Invitation to reception after Joseph Levi Leonard debut concert]. card; 1 p. (Box 20, Folder 25)
      Invitation from Pacific Institute of Music and Fine Art to Mr. Richard Lut for October 16, 1936.
    - [Letters of recommendation for Joseph Levi [Leonard]. type- and handwritten ms; onionskin; 11 p. (Box 21, Folder 11)
      10 items, in German: handwritten letter from Dr. Hugo Leichtentritt dated October 25, 1925; 2 typewritten letters from Franz Lange dated October 25, 1925 and September 6, 1923; typewritten letter from Max Mayer dated July 18, 1935; typewritten letter from Dr. Reichmann-Jungmann dated May 31, 1933; handwritten letter from Georg A. Walter, dated October 21, 1925; handwritten letter dated December 7, 1925 from [?] Papoff; mimeographed (2 pp.) compilation of letters of recommendation; mimeographed letter from Franz Lange dated October 25, 1925; mimeographed letter from Leon Korni[?] dated May 28, 1930.
    - [Compilation of letters of recommendation from German synagogues]. typewritten ms; 2 p. (Box 21, Folder 14)
      Letters date from May 8, 1931- July 18, 1935 and appear to be translated from German.
    - Papoff. Zeugniss. handwritten ms; 1 p. (Box 21, Folder 15)
      Letter in German dated December 27, 1925; possibly a letter of recommendation.
    - [Compilation of letters of recommendation]. mimeograph onionskin; 1 p. (Box 21, Folder 20)
      Letters from religious figures, dated 1931.
    - [Letter regarding immigration status of Joseph Levi [Leonard]]. mimeograph; 1 leaf. (Box 21, Folder 27)
      Letter dated December 4, 1937 from Aflred Leonard to Howard Bowman, American Consulate, Mexicali, Mexico.
- Newspapers, Newsletters, Magazines, Series IV.
  - C[entral] V[erein] Zeitung. newspaper; 12 pp. (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Dated December 9, 1932; published in Berlin; in German language.
  - Israelitisches Gemeindeblatt. newspaper; 24 pp. (Box 7, Folder 2)
    Dated December 9, 1930; published in Mannheim; in German language. 2 copies.
  - Jewish Community Press. magazine; 194 pp. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    Special [Jewish] New Year edition dated September 3, 1937; published in Los Angeles.
  - Diemanfenfer Zeitung. newspaper; 8 pp. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    Dated Monday, January 20, 1930; in German language.
  - Neue Mannheimer Zeitung. newspaper; 10 pp. (Box 7, Folder 5)
    Dated Thursday, July 5, 1928; published in Mannheim; in German language. 2 copies.
  - Pfalsische Run?chau. newspaper; 12 pp. (Box 7, Folder 6)
    Dated Thursday, July 21, 1927 in German language. 2 copies.
  - C[entral] V[erein] Zeitung. newspaper; 14 pp. (Box 7, Folder 7)
    Dated May 10, 1934; published in Berlin; in German language. 3 copies.
  - Simplicissimus. magazine; 12 pp. (Box 7, Folder 8)
    Issue 36 (40); no date or place of publication given. In German.
  - Von Deutsch-judischen Jugend 3(6/7) October 21, 1927. newspaper; 4 p. (Box 18, Folder 14)
    Newspaper in German contains reference to Alfred Levi (Leonard) bottom of p. 1; article entitled Tagungen vom Bundestag der Kaermaden 1927 by Alfred Levi (Leonard) on p 4. Original location in front of Alfred Leonard scrapbook. See 8/5.
  - Record Retailing March 1947. journal; 112 p. (Box 18, Folder 25)
    Contains article "Classic and Folk Music Discs Alone Have Made this Store Unique - and Successful" on Alfred Leonard and his Gateway to Music store on pp.32-34
  - Radio Life - week of March 23 [1947]. magazine; 40 p; clippings. (Box 18, Folder 26)
    5 items: complete magazine; 4 clippings from back page. Back page contains photograph of Alfred Leonard with short caption.
  - Circle - Jewish Music Notes Fall 1955. 4 p. (Box 18, Folder 30)
    Prepared by the National Jewish Music Council.
  - Jewish Community Press October 23, 1936. magazine; 28 p. (Box 18, Folder 32)
    Magazine contains review of Joseph Levi-Leonard Los Angeles debut concert on p.10.
  - Judisch-liberale Zeitung. 4 p. (Box 18, Folder 34)
    Berlin-based German langauge newspaper dated May 11, 1934 contains reference on p. 3 to Joseph Levi [Leonard] performance.
  - Diemasemser Zeitung. 8 p. (Box 18, Folder 35)
    Monday, January 20, 1930 issue with review of Joseph Levi [Leonard] concert on p. 3.
  - CIM Notes Summer 1972. 12 p. (Box 18, Folder 40)
    2 copies of journal which contains articles about Victor Babin in memorium.
- Clippings, Advertisements, Reviews, Series V.
  - Pertaining to P. Alfred Leonard, Subseries 1.
    - [Los Angeles Times May 4, 1947]. newpaper; 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 10)
      5 copies of section "Music and Musicians" p. 5-6 with article on Alfred Leonard's Music Guild. Original location inserted in Alfred Leonard's Music Guild scrapbook (see 7/9).
    - [Review of Paganini Quartet]. newspaper clipping; 1 p. (Box 17, Folder 28)
      Article on Music Guild sponsored Paganini Quartet concert. Review in Los Angeles Times dated Friday, December 5, 1947. Original location inserted in Alfred Leonard's Music Guild scrapbook. See 7/9.
    - [Clippings pertaining to Paganini Quartet sponsored by Music Guild]. clippings; 3 items. (Box 17, Folder 29)
      3 items: clipping from unidentified newpaper provided by Allen's Press Clipping Bureau dated October 22, 1948 with review of Music Guild's 4th season performance of Paganini Quartet; review by Patterson Greene from unidentified newspaper from second year of Paganini performance sponsored by Music Guild (no date); review of same concert as in item 2 from unidentified newspaper. All items originally located in front of Music Guild scrapbook. See 7/9.
    - Leonard, Alfred. Music in Nazi-Germany. magazine clipping; 2 leaves. (Box 17, Folder 30)
      Article from unidentified source summarizing Mr. Raabe's book on Nazi Germany and political impact on music. Original location of clipping in front of Alfred Leonard's scrapbook. See box 8/5.
    - Morton, Lawrence. Music Notes. magazine clipping; 2 leaves. (Box 17, Folder 31)
      Clipping from Rob Wagner's Script magazine dated February 15, 1947 reviewing Music Guild performances of Klemperer conducting Bach program. Original location of article in front of Alfred Leonard's Music Guild scrapbook. See box 7/9.
    - Morton, Lawrence. Tops in Quartets. magazine clipping; 2 leaves. (Box 17, Folder 32)
      Review from Rob Wagner's Script magazine of Music Guild's sponsored performance of the Budapest Quartet dated October 26, 1946. Original location of clipping in front of Alfred Leonard's Music Guild scrapbook. See box 7/9.
    - Morton, Lawrence. Music Notes. magazine clipping; 3 leaves. (Box 17, Folder 33)
      Article from Rob Wagner's Script magazine reviewing Music Guild sponsored performance of London Quartet dated March 30, 1946. Original location of clipping in front of Alfred Leonard's Music Guild scrapbook. See box 7/9.
    - "An Interview with the Gateway to Music's Genial Alfred Leonard". xerox of newspaper clipping; 2 p. (Box 17, Folder 35)
      Clipping from Westwood Hills Press, Friday March 8, 1946. Original location in front of Alfred Leonard scrapbook. See 8/5.
    - Leonard, Alfred. On the Record - Notes for Phonophiles and Disco-maniacs. magazine; 34 p. (Box 17, Folder 36)
      Article located on p. 15 of complete magazine issue of Rob Wagner's Script vol. 19 no. 485, dated June 4, 1938. Magazine originally folded open to p. 15. Original location in front of Alfred Leonard scrapbook. See 8/5.
    - Leonard, Alfred. On the Record - Surface Noise and Vibrant Beauty. magazine; 34 p. (Box 17, Folder 37)
      Article on p. 26 of Rob Wagner's Script vol. 29, no. 469. Magazine originally folded open to p. 26. Original location in front of Alfred Leonard scrapbook. See 8/5.
    - Leonard, Alfred. Music in the Air. newsletter clipping; 1 leaf. (Box 18, Folder 4)
      Article from March 13, 1936 issue of Jewish Community Press, p. 17. Original location in front of Alfred Leonard scrapbook. See 8/5.
    - [Reviews of various records and reel-to-reel tapes]. onionskin; 2 p. (Box 18, Folder 18)
      Reviews of Franck Symphony in D minor; Robert Shaw performance of Bach B Minor Mass; taped versions of Otello and other November releases. Possibly prepared by Alfred Leonard.
    - Convention Daily no. 2; July 10-13, 1950. newsletter; 6 p. (Box 18, Folder 20)
      Full title of newsletter "Convention Daily - A Service of Record Retailing Magazine". P. 2 contains quote from Alfred Leonard of Gateway to Music.
    - [Gateway to Music ad]. magazine clipping; 1 leaf. (Box 18, Folder 21)
      Unidentified source.
    - [Article on Alfred Leonard appointment to RCA Red Seal merchandizing]. photostat; 1 p. (Box 18, Folder 22)
      3 copies of clipping from Variety October 8, 1958.
    - Cariaga, Daniel. "Music Guild: 40 Years at the Center". newspaper clipping; 1 leaf. (Box 18, Folder 23)
      Pp. 53-54 of Los Angeles Times Calendar section, Sunday October 21, 1984.
    - Harford, Margaret. [Article on Alfred Leonard's Music Guild concert featuring Artur Schnabel]. newspaper cipping; 1 leaf. (Box 18, Folder 24)
      2 copies of pp. 7-8 of Hollywood Citizen-News, Tuesday, October 1, 1946.
    - Shippey, Lee. [Article with reference to Alfred Leonard's Gateway to Music store]. newspaper clipping; 1 leaf; article clipping. (Box 19, Folder 1)
      5 copies, of newspaper section, 1 copy of article clipping of pp. 3-4 of Los Angeles Times Wednesday morning, January 14, 1948. Article "Leeside" contains paragraph "Shuns popularity" which refers to Gateway to Music store.
    - Shippey, Lee. [Article covering Music Guild and Alfred Leonard]. newspaper clipping; 1 leaf. (Box 19, Folder 2)
      Pp. 3-4 of Los Angeles Times Wednesday morning, September 11, 1946.
  - Pertaining to Joseph Leonard, Subseries 2.
    - [Compilation of reviews of Joseph Levi [Leonard]'s performances]. 1 p. (Box 17, Folder 13)
      5 copies retained out of approx. 50 copies which were located with items in 17/12. Compilation of reviews in German from newspapers dating November 11, 1924 to July 27, 1926, with Joseph Levi [Leonard]'s address and phone number in Mannheim.
    - Blind lead 'Lights Festival'. newspaper clipping; 1 p. (Box 18, Folder 1)
      Clipping dated Thursday December 15, 1966 with photograph and short caption about Joseph Leonard leading Hanukah celebration at Temple Beth Am. Original location in front of Alfred Leonard scrapbook. See 8/5.
    - [Reviews of Joseph Leonard's playing]. clipping from concert program; 1 leaf (partial). (Box 18, Folder 6)
      Reviews on back of unidentified concert program of Joseph Leonard and Genevieve Wiley performance. Original location in front of Alfred Leonard scrapbook, clipped to Joseph Leonard material. See 8/5.
    - [Tribute to Joseph Leonard by Temple Beth Am]. clippings; 4 leaves+article clipping. (Box 18, Folder 11)
      2 items announcing tribute to Joseph Leonard: clipping fromn unidentified newspaper announcing tribute to be held December 9; pp. 15-16; 29-30 of B'nai Brith Messenger announcing tribute dated December 6, 1963. Original location in front of Alfred Leonard scrapbook. See 8/5.
    - [Music Review - Inglewood Symphony with Joseph Leonard, soloist]. 2 leaves. (Box 18, Folder 16)
      Pp. 11-12; 25-26 of Daily News, Los Angeles dated Tuesday, May 26, 1953. Original location in front of Alfred Leonard scrapbook. See 8/5.
    - [Review of Joseph Levi [Leonard] performance]. magazine clipping; 1 leaf. (Box 18, Folder 28)
      Pp. 13-14 of Israelitisches Gemeindeblatt March 15, 1934 with article on p. 13 "'Beethoven - Abend' in der C. V. - Jugend".
    - [Review of tribute to Joseph Leonard]. magazine clipping; 1 leaf. (Box 18, Folder 29)
      Pp.25-26 of The Diapason January 1964, with article on p. 25.
    - [Press release for Joseph Leonard Bach-Beethoven recital]. 1 p. (Box 18, Folder 31)
      Press release for Los Angeles debut performance of Joseph Levi-Leonard on October 16.
    - [Clipping concerning performance of Joseph Levi [Leonard]]. newspaper clipping; 1 leaf. (Box 18, Folder 33)
      Pp. 3-4 of Neue Mannheimer Zeitung, February 11, 1928.
    - [Review of Joseph Levi [Leonard] concert]. newspaper clipping; 1 leaf. (Box 18, Folder 36)
      Pp. 1-2 of Mannheimer Tageblatt Wednesday March 24, 1926. Review is on p. 2.
    - [Review of Joseph Levi [Leonard] concert]. newspaper clipping; 1 leaf. (Box 18, Folder 37)
      Pp. 3-4 of Neue Mannheimer Zeitung, Friday, July 27, 1928. Review is on p. 4.
    - [Press release re Joseph Levi-Leonard's appointment to Pacific Institute faculty. 1 p. (Box 18, Folder 41)
      Press release prepared by Pacific Institute of Music and Fine Art.
    - [Review of Joseph Levi [Leonard] performance]. clipping; 1 leaf. (Box 19, Folder 3)
      2 copies of pp. 3-4 of Mannheim Tageblatt, February 19, 1930.
    - [Announcement of Joseph Leonard performance]. newspaper clipping; 1 leaf. (Box 19, Folder 4)
      Pp. 1-2 of Los Angeles Times July 19, 1940 with article"Blind soloist tops program".
    - [Annoucement of Joseph Leonard concert]. newspaper clipping; 2 leaves. (Box 19, Folder 5)
      2 copies of pp. 5-8 of Los Angeles Examiner Sunday July 21, 1940, with article "Blind soloist".
    - [Review of Joseph Leonard with Boston Pops Orchestra]. newspaper clipping; 1 leaf. (Box 19, Folder 6)
      Pp. 12-13 of Los Angeles Times Monday morning July 22, 1940 with article "'Pops' Orchestra Blows in".
    - [Announcement of Joseph Levi [Leonard] concert]. newspaper clipping; 1 leaf. (Box 19, Folder 7)
      2 copies of pp. 3-4 of German language newspaper Bfalaische Bundschau January 19, 1930 with article on p. 4 "Konzert in Birmasens".
    - Jones, Isabel Morse. [Review of Joseph Levi-Leonard concert]. newspaper clipping; 1 leaf. (Box 19, Folder 9)
      Pp. 7-8 of Los Angeles Times, October 17, 1936; p. 7 contains review, "Gifted Young Pianist Plays Bach and Beethoven".
    - Jones, Isabel Morse. [Announcement of Joseph Levi-Leonard concert]. newspaper clipping; 1 leaf. (Box 19, Folder 10)
      Pp. 5-6 of Los Angeles Times, October 11, 1936; p. 5 contains brief announcement of Joseph Levi-Leonard concert.
    - van Gundum, Palmer. [Review of Joseph Levi-Leonard recital]. newspaper clipping; 1 leaf. (Box 19, Folder 11)
      Pp. 5-6 of Hollywood Citizen-News, Saturday, October 17, 1936; p. 5 contains article "Levi-Leonard Applauded in Piano Recital".
    - [Announcement of wedding]. newspaper clipping; 2 leaves. (Box 19, Folder 12)
      Pp. 11-12; 17-18 of Hollywood Citizen-News, Saturday, October 17, 1936; p. 11 contains article about wedding in which Joseph Levin[sic] Leonard played.
    - [Announcement of Temple Beth Am 25th Anniversary]. newspaper clipping; 1 leaf. (Box 19, Folder 13)
      Pp. 11-12 of The Pico Post - The Beverly Post, Thursday, February 16, 1960; p. 12 contains announcement of Temple Beth Am 25th Anniversary with Joseph Leonard, organist.
    - [Announcement of Los Angeles Pops concert with Joseph Leonard]. newspaper clipping; 1 leaf. (Box 19, Folder 14)
      Pp. 3-4 Los Angeles Times, July 20, 1940; p. 3 contains announcement of Los Angeles Pops concert with Joseph Leonard, pianist.
    - [Announcement of Los Angeles Pops concert with Joseph Leonard]. newspaper clipping; 1 leaf. (Box 19, Folder 15)
      Pp. 5-6 of Los Angeles Times, Sunday, July 21, 1940; announcement of Los Angeles Pops concert with Joseph Leonard, soloist.
    - [Announcement of Los Angeles Pops concert with Joseph Leonard]. newspaper clipping; 1 leaf. (Box 19, Folder 16)
      Pp. 7-8 of Los Angeles Evening Herald and Express, Saturday, July 20, 1940; p. 8 contains article "Jos. Leonard to be Concert Soloist".
    - [Review of Joseph Levi Leonard's Los Angeles debut concert]. mimeograph copy; 1 p. (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - [Compilation of reviews from German sources]. onionskin; 1 p. (Box 20, Folder 33)
      Reviews date from March 8 - May 22, 1931.
    - [Compilation of German-language reviews]. onionskin; 5 p. (Box 21, Folder 13)
      Date of reviews from June 6, 1927 - April 12, 1935.
  - Pertaining to Ernst Toch, Subseries 3.
    - [Reviews of Ernst Toch 1st Symphony performances]. onionskin, typed ms; 1 p. (Box 18, Folder 19)
      Reviews in German compiled from various newspaper sources.
    - [Reviews of Toch Second Piano Concerto]. xerox; 1 p. (Box 19, Folder 8)
      Reviews from Boston Globe, Christian Science Monitor, and unidentified newspaper source 1938.
    - [Reviews of Toch Symphony no. 2]. microfiche copy; 2 p; xerox; 2 p; handritten ms note; 1 p. (Box 20, Folder 2)
      5 items: handwritten note in red pen (by Eleanor Rubin?) attached to reviews and to item in 20/1; microfiche copy of reviews from Christian Science Monitor (December 13, 1952), Boston Post (n.d.), Boston Herald (n.d.); microfiche copy of reviews from Los Angeles Mirror (November 21, 1953), Los Angeles Times (November 21, 1952), Los Angeles Daily News (November 21, 1952), Los Angeles Examiner (n.d.); xerox of typewritten compilation of reviews from Swiss press; xerox of reviews from Minneapolis (September 13, 1954); Minneapolis Star (November 13, 1954).
    - [Reviews of performance of Toch works]. xerox; 3 p. (Box 20, Folder 3)
      3 items, German language reviews of Toch's works as performed by Daniel Barenboim and Rundfunk Symphony Orchestra: from Sueddeutschen Zeitung no. 137 June 9, 1970; from Abendzeitung Muenchen June 1, 1970; from T. Z. Muenchen June 1, 1970.
    - Goldberg, Albert. Composer-Philosopher Toch Speaks Out. newspaper clipping; 1 leaf. (Box 20, Folder 4)
      P. 11-12 from Los Angeles Times Calendar Sunday December 2, 1962; article on p. 11 with drawing of Toch.
    - [Reviews from German press of Toch symphony]. xerox; 1 p. (Box 20, Folder 5)
      Compilation of reviews dating from December 12, 1950 - January 19, 1951.
    - [Photo from newspaper clipping]. clipping; 1 p. (Box 20, Folder 6)
      Photo from unidentified newspaper source, post 1964.
  - Pertaining to Babin-Vronsky, Subseries 4.
    - [Articles on Victor Babin in memorium]. xerox; 3 p. (Box 20, Folder 7)
      5 sets of xeroxes of articles on Victor Babin from CIM Notes Summer 1972 (see 18/40 for original journal).